STEPHANIE THOMPSON

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

CONTACT

- 817.521.9221
- https://stephcodes.dev
- in linkedin.com/in/stephthomp
- github.com/Rocklobster84

EDUCATION

B.S. Computer Science

Southern New Hampshire University Manchester, NH | 2020

VOLUNTEER

Women Who Code DFW

Helped attendees sign in, photographed events, and presented a workshop that I created:

Mini Workshop: Sending Email with PHP | 2019

HOBBIES

Photography, Hiking, Gardening, Music, Crochet

SUMMARY

I am a passionate and experienced Full Stack Developer with a track record of designing, building, and deploying web applications. I am skilled in the latest web technologies and have over 9 years of experience. I am currently seeking a team where I can continue to learn and grow while contributing my skills and expertise.

SKILLS

- Node.js / Apache
- HTML / CSS
- JavaScript / Typescript
- Express.js / React
- SQL / NoSQL
- RESTful Routing

- MongoDB
- CI / CD
- API / REST
- AWS / GCP / Azure
- Jenkins
- PHP / Python / Flask
- Chef / Ruby / DevOps

- GIT / GitHub
- XML/JSON
- jQeury / AJAX
- Terraform
- Docker
- JWT
- Agile

EXPERIENCE

PROFESSIONAL SERVICES CONSULTANT

PROGRESS SOFTWARE \mid REMOTELY FROM N RICHLAND HILLS, TX \mid MAR 2022 - NOV 2023

- Provided Chef software customer training which included DevOps fundamentals, source control with Git and GitHub, unit and integration testing, and pipeline creation using Jenkins.
- Assisted in the development of new Chef content and contributed to the design and usability of cutting-edge on-demand learning and certification platform.
- Delivered professional services to international and domestic clients, which included reviewing existing customer implementations of Chef and working to resolve customer issues.

STEPHANIE THOMPSON

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

SENIOR FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

CADENCE DESIGN SYSTEMS, ACQUIRED POINTWISE, INC. IN 2021 \mid FORT WORTH, TX \mid FEB 2015 - JAN 2022

- Continued support of the Pointwise web application after acquisition by maintaining the existing REST API.
- Converted several components of the Pointwise web application to Cadence's Adobe AEM implementation.
- Assisted the IT department with the migration of various infrastructure products, data, and processes.
- Converted legacy website to modern, responsive web application utilizing Node.js, Express.js, Bootstrap 4, and MongoDB. https://www.pointwise.com.
- Consulted with the Engineering Services department on the design and development of an online user manual and Teachable online courses.
- Managed web servers to keep all packages and dependencies up to date.
- Improved existing bash scripts used for deployment.
- Made site speed adjustments that caused a 9% increase in traffic YOY 2019-2020, and a 27% increase in traffic YOY first quarter 2020-2021.